# JULIE SEIGLE

(774) 249-3280 | seiglejl@gmail.com | W-2 Authorized | Boston, MA

Linkedin: Click Here | Github: Click Here

## Software Engineer

#### EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Experience Software Developer with extensive experience in developing applications in Python, Flask, SQL, JavaScript and React. Experience in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle. Projects applied in Agile Methodology. Strong analytical and problem-solving skills while utilizing multiple programming languages and technologies.

Proactive leader and an efficient team-player with the ability to be influential and establish positive working relationships across the organization.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages Python, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQLite, jQuery, SQL

Web Technologies/Development Frameworks Web Forms, Flask, API, React, JS, SASS, Json, Ajax, Pandas,

**B**ootstrap

Database PostgreSQL, Firebase, MySQL

Tools/Methodologies Jupyter Notebook, Atom, Visual Studio 2017, Anaconda,

Google Developer Tools, Heroku, Google Web Designer,

Stripe API

Software Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Git, Github

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

## Project 1: Photogram

Create a photo sharing website, where the users can log in, post photos and make comments using Python, Flask, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Heroku

Project 2: Ecommerce \_ Twitter

Create an ecommerce website, where the users can log in, post tweet and select and pay for the products using Python, Flask, Bootstrap, Stripe API, and Heroku

Project 3: Scheduler

Create an event scheduler, where the users can make, save and search for the events scheduled using Python, JavaScript, Flask, React, JS and SQLite

#### COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

#### BOSTON PYTHON USER GROUP & CODING TEMPLE, MA

Event Assistant March 19th, 2019

- Helped in developing ideas & guidelines for a beginner level python evening class.
- Successfully clarified questions for several attendees.
- Connected with Ned Betchelder, and am now an active member of TBPUG.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### CODING TEMPLE-BOSTON, MA

Software Developer

Oct 2018 - Present

- Wireframe and design Web Applications.
- Use HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap UI.
- Add new feature requests, fixed bugs and trouble shoot.
- Develop E-Commerce application using HTML5, CSS3, Python, SQL, Flask, JavaScript and Web API's.
- Build Front-End and Back-End applications.

#### JAPAN ASIA PROMOTION FOUNDATION, JAPAN

International Program Leader

Apr 2016 - Aug 2018

- Acted as liaison between tour leaders to resolve participant conflicts and issues.
- Managed committee of 30 university students to streamline the process of tour preparation.
- Doubled student enrollment of study programs to Cambodia.
- Provided 24hour support during study tours.
- Published articles and email magazines monthly for Cambodia-related organizations.
- Designed and edited posters, leaflets and website for tours and events.
- Guided a study tour group in Vietnam.
- Advised on student committee's budget.
- Created the training manual for new employees.

#### TOKYO POWER ENERGY, JAPAN

Billing Analyst

Jul 2016 - Aug 2018

- As a founding member, developed business operations and strategy.
- Served as a front desk position for Tokyo Power Energy.
- Presented accurate trial electricity calculations and contract documents.
- Resolved customer issues in a timely manner.

#### ASHIYA GAKUEN JUNIOR / SENIOR HIGH SCHOOL, JAPAN

**English Teacher** 

Apr 2016 - Jul 2017

• Taught English to junior-high school, high school and professionals.

## **EDUCATION**

## KOBE CITY UNIVERSITY OF FOREIGN STUDIES, JAPAN

Bachelor of Arts in Foreign Studies (Spanish)

Apr 2012 - Mar 2016

## ABOUT ME

#### **Green Card Holder**

LANGUAGES: Japanese (Native); English (Fluent); Spanish (Intermediate).

OTHERS: Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite